A Guide to the George Edward Bates papers, 1903-1963
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
George Edward Bates papers, 1903-1963
The Library of Virginia
53902
.225 cubic feet (1 box)
George Edward Bates
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Purchased.
Biographical Information
George Edward Bates was born 13 August 1874 in Delaware County, Pennsylvania, to George Bates (1831-1892) and Sarah Marshall Bates (1833-1892). George Bates worked for several railroad companies, including the Delaware and Hudson Railway Company. He married Mary Howard Lamb (1874-1942) in May 1897, and they had two daughters. Bates died in Albany, New York, 2 March 1955, and is buried in Albany Rural Cemetery.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1903-1963, of George Edward Bates (1874-1955) of Philadelphia and Scranton, Pennsylvania, and Albany, New York, concerning a lot he owned in the East Fairmount neighborhood in Norfolk County, Virginia, including his daughter Eva Marshall Bates Weaver's (1898-1993) effort to sell it after his death. Papers also include correspondence regarding the maintenance of his parents' graves in Calvary Episcopal Church in Delaware County, Pennsylvania, and George Bates' retirement from the Delaware and Hudson Railway Company.
Contents List
- Correspondence, 1903-1905 (Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1907-1909 (Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1911-1915 (Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1916-1921 (Folder 4)
- Correspondence, 1922-1923 (Folder 5)
- Correspondence, 1924-1926 (Folder 6)
- Correspondence, 1927-1928 (Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1930-1942 (Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 1950-1955 (Folder 9)
- Correspondence regarding upkeep of parents graves at Calvary Episcopal Church, Delaware County, Pennsylvania, 1934 (Folder 10)
- Correspondence regarding retirement, 1944 (Folder 11)
- Correspondence regarding Eva Marshall Bates Weaver's efforts to sell East Fairmount property, 196-1963 (Folder 12)
- East Fairmount property, 1905-1963 (Folder 13)
- George Edward Bates estate papers, 1955-1963 (Folder 14)
- General papers, 1908-1944 (Folder 15)